Guide to the Contest responses to Lenore Skenazy's "Only in New York" and "New York Stories" columns, New York Daily News, 1988-1995 MS 3232
New-York Historical Society
Contest responses to Lenore Skenazy's "Only in New York" and "New York Stories" columns, New York Daily News
1988-1995
New-York Historical Society
Daily news (New York, N.Y.: 1920)
Skenazy, Lenore
MS 3232
4.587 Linear feet in 11 document boxes.
Submissions by readers of the New York Daily News to weekly contests run in Lenore Skenazy's "Only in New York" and "New York Stories" Sunday magazine columns, in which they answered questions designed to elicit entertaining responses that could only happen to true New Yorkers.
Access Restrictions
This collection is stored offsite. To arrange to consult it, please go to www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Lenore Skenazy, 1992, 1995.
Arrangement
The collection is organized in two series:
Series I. "Only in New York" contest responses, 1988-1990
Series II. "New York Stories" contest responses, 1992-1995
Biographical note
Although perhaps best know for her then-controversial New York Sun article, "Why I Let My 9-Year-Old Ride the Subway Alone" (2008), subsequent book, "Free Range Kids: How to Raise Safe, Self-Reliant Children (Without Going Nuts With Worry)" (2009), and her activism for the "free-range parenting" movement, Lenore Skenazy has had a long career in journalism. Before moving to the short-lived New York Sun (folded 2008), Skenazy was for fourteen years a regular contributor to the New York Daily News, where her byline headed the "Only in New York" and "New York Stories" Sunday magazine columns.
Related Materials
Note that the New-York Historical Society does not hold the New York Daily News for the time period covered by the present collection, 1988-1995. The paper has been digitized, and is accessible via the subscription site Newspapers.com.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of letters—some typed, most handwritten, and some on postcards—submitted by readers of the New York Daily News hoping to win one of the weekly contests run in Lenore Skenazy's "Only in New York" and "New York Stories" columns in the Sunday magazine section. The "Only in New York" contests ran from 1988 through at least 1990; the "New York Stories" contests from 1991 or 1992 through 1995 or later. Each week Skenazy posed a question (some of them reworked from previous contests) in which readers were asked to describe the most disappointing thing to have happened on a vacation, or the most creative way they tortured a sibling (or vice versa), or the strangest thing they witnessed at a funeral, or the wildest pickup line they ever used or heard. (See the container list for the complete questions for the entries in the collection; note that the collection is incomplete.) From the most entertaining submissions Skenazy published first, second, and third place winners. In addition to the pleasure of seeing their words in print, winners could expect to receive a "Handsome Keepsake Contest Winner's Plaque" (for "Only in New York") or a t-shirt with the column title printed on it (for "New York Stories).
Contests.; Journalists.; Newspapers -- Sections, columns, etc.; Competition entries.; Letters (correspondence); New York (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century.; Daily news (New York, N.Y.: 1920)
- Series I. "Only in New York" contest responses, 1988-1990
  Arrangement
  The collection remains in its original folders, which were marked by Lenore Skenazy with their contest number and an abbreviated and/or paraphrased version of the contest question posed. The container list includes the verbatim questions as recorded in the Daily News, followed by the date the results of each contest were published. "ONY" before each file name stands for "Only in New York."
  - Tear sheets and photocopies of published "Only in New York" contests (scattered) (Offsite-box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    • ONY Contest 2. {How do you choose your lottery numbers?} [results published September 4, 1988]
    • ONY Contest 11. What was the most bizarre thing you ever witnessed on New York public transportation? [results published November 6, 1988]
    • ONY Contest 16. What's the one thing about holidays, apart from crowds, we mean, that makes you craziest? [results published December 11, 1988]
    • ONY Contest 23. How did your mom and dad meet? [results published February 5, 1989]
    • ONY Contest 25. A genuinely appropriate New York fortune cookie fortune. [results published February 19, 1989]
    • ONY Contest 31. What's your favorite New York cockroach story? [results published April 16, 1989]
    • ONY Contest 33. What was your worst experience with a rude New York salesperson? [results published April 30, 1989]
    • ONY Contest 40. The most incredibly annoying colleague you've ever dealt with. [results published June 18, 1989]
    • ONY Contest 46. What would you like to find when (and if) you get to heaven? [results published July 30, 1989]
    • ONY Contest 54. What was the most useless and irrelevant piece of advice your nice old grandparents ever gave you? [results published September 24, 1989]
    • ONY Contest 61. What was the most traumatic thing that happened to you in elementary school? [results published November 12, 1989]
    • ONY Contest 63. The stranger you never thanked. [results published November 26, 1989]
    • ONY Contest 71. What was the best time you ever had at Rockefeller Center? [results published January 28, 1990]
    • ONY Contest 73. How did your sweetie propose? [results published February 11, 1990]
    • ONY Contest 82. Your most obnoxious customer. [results published April 22, 1990]
  - ONY Contest 47. What was the most disappointing thing that ever happened to you on a vacation? [results published August 6, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 48. What's the worst thing your roommate, past or present, ever did to you? [results August 13, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 49. What was the greatest rip-off you've ever experienced in this city? [results published August 20, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 50. What was your worst birthday party ever? [results published August 27, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 51. What is the most amazing tale a panhandler has ever laid on you? [results published September 3, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 52. What one thing went wrong at your wedding (or a wedding you attended)? [results published September 10, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 53. Send us a photo of yourself and tell us what famous person you think you look like. [results published September 17, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 54. What was the most useless and irrelevant piece of advice your nice old grandparents ever gave you? [results published September 24, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 55. What is the one piece of good useful New York trivia that you happen to know but probably very few other people know? [results published October 1, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 56. A campaign slogan for Batman for Mayor. [results published October 8, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 57. Ode to the New York shove. [results published October 15, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 58. I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry I did... (whatever). [results published October 22, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 59. What one letter would you like to write to a New York TV personality? / What one letter would you like to pen to your New York public? [results published October 29, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 60. What did you want to be when you grew up, how close did you ever get—and how did you end up doing what you're doing now? [results published November 5, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 61. What was the most traumatic thing that happened to you in elementary school? [results published November 12, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 62. What's the nicest thing a New York shopkeeper ever did for you? [results published November 19, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 63. The stranger you never thanked. [results published November 26, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 64. A provable truth about New York City. [results published December 3, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 65. Where can we find your favorite ethnic food in New York and what makes it unusual? [results published December 10, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 66. What was the weirdest diet you ever went on? [results published December 17, 1989] (Offsite-box 1)
  - ONY Contest 67. What was the worst present you ever got for Christmas of Chanukah? [results published December 24, 1989] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 68. What was the most amazing thing that ever happened at an office party you attended? [results published January 7, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 69. What was your personal high point of the '80s? [results published January 14, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 70. An ode to and about Ed Koch from his faithful constituents who loved him so. [results published January 21, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 71. What was the best time you ever had at Rockefeller Center? [results published January 28, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 72. What was the hardest thing to get used to about your in-laws? [results published February 4, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 73. How did your sweetie propose? [results published February 11, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 74. What was your most exasperating babysitting experience? [results published February 18, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 75. A typical conversation with your mother. [results published February 25, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 76. What was the most amazing exchange you ever had with a cab driver? [results published March 4, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 77. What was the weirdest class you ever took at night school? [results published March 11, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 78. Your imaginary childhood friend. [results published March 18, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 79. The now-extinct New York landmark whose loss you regret the most. (March 25, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 80. What's the lamest excuse you've ever given/heard to get out of trouble with the law? [results published April 1, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 81. A typical conversation with your son or daughter. [results published April 8, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 82. Your most obnoxious customer. [results published April 22, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 83. The New Yorker you knew before he or she became famous. [results published April 29, 1990] (Offsite-box 2)
  - ONY Contest 84. What was your first impression of your honey? [results published May 6, 1990] (Offsite-box 3)
  - ONY Contest 85. A picture of yourself and your pet. [results published May 13, 1990] (Offsite-box 3)
  - ONY Contest 86. What was the best time you ever had at a baseball game? [results published May 20, 1990] (Offsite-box 3)
  - ONY Contest 87. What did you do on a typical Saturday night when you were 17 years old? [results published May 27, 1990] (Offsite-box 3)
  - ONY Contest 88. The most awful person you ever sat next to on a plane, train, boat, or bus. [results published June 3, 1990] (Offsite-box 3)
  - ONY Contest 89. What's the shortest time you ever held a job? [results published June 10, 1990] (Offsite-box 3)
  - ONY Contest 90. What urban clues tell you it's summer? [results published June 24, 1990] (Offsite-box 3)
  - ONY Contest 91. What song have you always mis-sung the words to? [results published July 29, 1990] (Offsite-box 3)
  - ONY Contest 92. Under what circumstances was an item returned to you unexpectedly? [results published July 1, 1990] (Offsite-box 3)
  - ONY Contest 93. What's the best nickname you or a pal ever had? [results published July 8, 1990] (Offsite-box 3)
- Series II. "New York Stories" contest responses, 1992-1995
  The collection remains in its original folders, which were marked by Lenore Skenazy with their contest number and an abbreviated and/or paraphrased version of the contest question posed. The container list includes the verbatim questions as recorded in the Daily News, followed by the date the results of each contest were published. "NYS" before each file name stands for "New York Stories."
  - Tear sheets and photocopies of published "New York Stories" contests (scattered) (Offsite-box 4)
    • NYS Contest 19. The least relaxing vacation you ever endured! [results published March 22, 1992]
    • NYS Contest 25. Proof that your pet is a genius (or at least pretty darn clever). [results published May 3, 1992]
    • NYS Contest 27. What's the silliest thing you ever said in another language—accidentally, of course? [results published May 17, 1992]
    • NYS Contest 34. What's the strangest thing you ever witnessed at one of New York's parks or beaches? [results published July 5, 1992]
    • NYS Contest 37. What character did you play in make-believe? And what was the basic scenario? [results published July 26, 1992]
    • NYS Contest 38. What's the wildest thing you ever did when you came face to face with a celebrity? [results published August 2, 1992]
  - NYS Contest 74. What neighbor drove you nuts? [results published April 11, 1993] (Offsite-box 4)
  - NYS Contest 75. What childhood incident does your brother or sister still tease you about? [results published April 18, 1993] (Offsite-box 4)
  - NYS Contest 76. What's the most memorable question you kid (or a kid you know) ever asked? [results published April 25, 1993] (Offsite-box 4)
  - NYS Contest 77. What strange thing happened to you because of your name? [results published May 2, 1993] (Offsite-box 4)
  - NYS Contest 78. What's the most drastic step you ever took toward improving your mind, body or circumstances in general? [results published May 9, 1993] (Offsite-box 4)
  - NYS Contest 79. What was the least-perfect quality time you ever spent? [results published May 16, 1993] (Offsite-box 4)
  - NYS Contest 80. What one thing would you like your former teacher to know about you? And why? [results published May 23, 1993] (Offsite-box 4)
  - NYS Contest 81. When did you make a public flub? And did anyone notice? [results published May 30, 1993] (Offsite-box 4)
  - NYS Contest 82. What superstitious little thing do you do... even though it may be dumb? [results published June 6, 1993] (Offsite-box 4)
  - NYS Contest 83. What waiter or waitress will you always remember... fondly or otherwise? [results published June 13, 1993] (Offsite-box 4)
  - NYS Contest 84. When did you appear to be crazy in public? [results published June 20, 1993] (Offsite-box 4)
  - NYS Contest 85. What personal story of yours from the 1960s says it all? [results published June 27, 1993] (Offsite-box 5)
  - NYS Contest 86. What fact did you have seriously wrong when you were a kid? (Or what facts did someone else you know believe?) [results published July 4, 1993] (Offsite-box 5)
  - NYS Contest 87. What's the wildest pickup line you've ever used... or heard? [results published July 11, 1993] (Offsite-box 5)
  - NYS Contest 88. What's the most embarrassing thing your mother ever did in front of you? (Preferably in public, of course.) [results published July 18, 1993] (Offsite-box 5)
  - NYS Contest 89. What sign made a lasting impression on you? [results published July 25, 1993] (Offsite-box 5)
  - NYS Contest 90. What makes you suspect that your pet may be part human? (That goes for pets in your past, too.) [results published August 1, 1993] (Offsite-box 5)
  - NYS Contest 91. What's the most foreign thing you ever found yourself doing? (At home or abroad!) [results published August 8, 1993] (Offsite-box 5)
  - NYS Contest 92. What's the weirdest bet you ever made? [results published August 15, 1993] (Offsite-box 5)
  - NYS Contest 93. When did you have to pretend you were something you weren't? (And how did you pull it off?) [results published August 22, 1993] (Offsite-box 5)
  - NYS Contest 94. What ice cream experience will you never forget? [results published August 29, 1993] (Offsite-box 5)
  - NYS Contest 95. What foreign word or phrase snuck into your vocabulary? (And, if you remember, how'd it get there?) [results published September 5, 1993] (Offsite-box 5)
  - NYS Contest 96. What's the strangest way you ever first met a friend? [results published September 12, 1993] (Offsite-box 6)
  - NYS Contest 97. What's the very strangest thing you ever found yourself ingesting? (And why?) [results published September 19, 1993] (Offsite-box 6)
  - NYS Contest 98. What song always brings back memories you'd rather forget? [results published September 26, 1993] (Offsite-box 6)
  - NYS Contest 99. What one incident made you realize you were or were not popular in high school? [results published October 3, 1993] (Offsite-box 6)
  - NYS Contest 100. How has the Daily News had a direct impact on your life? [results published October 10, 1993] (Offsite-box 6)
  - NYS Contest 101. What is the one thing you do completely different from someone you're close to? [results published October 17, 1993] (Offsite-box 6)
  - NYS Contest 102. What was the most traumatic thing that happened to you on or around the first day of school? [results published October 24, 1993] (Offsite-box 6)
  - NYS Contest 103. What mechanical device did you finally conquer? How awful was it? [results published October 31, 1993] (Offsite-box 6)
  - NYS Contest 104. What one place were you dying to get to... then dying to get away from? [results published November 7, 1993] (Offsite-box 6)
  - NYS Contest 105. What was the silliest lie you ever uttered and were there any weird consequences? [results published November 14, 1993] (Offsite-box 6)
  - NYS Contest 106. What's the most amazing thing you ever witnessed on public transportation? [results published November 21, 1993] (Offsite-box 6)
  - NYS Contest 107. What's the wildest thing you ever witnessed in a bar? [results published November 28, 1993] (Offsite-box 7)
  - NYS Contest 108. How did your pet prove that he/she is no genius? [results published December 5, 1993] (Offsite-box 7)
  - NYS Contest 109. What's the weirdest thing a relative of yours ever did at a family gathering? [results published December 12, 1993] (Offsite-box 7)
  - NYS Contest 110. What was your worst cooking disaster? [results published December 19, 1993] (Offsite-box 7)
  - NYS Contest 111. What's the weirdest dream you ever had? [results published December 26, 1993] (Offsite-box 7)
  - NYS Contest 112. What's your most amazing New York car story? [results published January 2, 1994] (Offsite-box 7)
  - NYS Contest 113. What happened to you after your most amazingly good or bad haircut? [results published January 9, 1994] (Offsite-box 7)
  - NYS Contest 114. What is the sweetest, dumbest nickname you've given to someone (or something) you love? [results published January 16, 1994] (Offsite-box 7)
  - NYS Contest 115. What incident, big or small, made you believe in basic human goodness? [results published January 23, 1994] (Offsite-box 7)
  - NYS Contest 116. What's the strangest thing that happened at a wake or funeral you attended? [results published January 30, 1994] (Offsite-box 7)
  - NYS Contest 117. What was the most disappointing present you ever received, on any occasion? [results published February 6, 1994] (Offsite-box 7)
  - NYS Contest 118. Under what circumstances did you receive your most surprising kiss? [results published February 13, 1994] (Offsite-box 7)
  - NYS Contest 119. What's the strangest way you ever got a job? [results published February 20, 1994] (Offsite-box 7)
  - NYS Contest 120. What made you feel like a grownup when you were just a kid? [results published February 27, 1994] (Offsite-box 7)
  - NYS Contest 121. What happened on your cheapest date ever? [results published March 6, 1994] (Offsite-box 8)
  - NYS Contest 122. What's the most memorable thing that ever happened to you on jury duty? [results published March 13, 1994] (Offsite-box 8)
  - NYS Contest 123. What is your family's favorite story about your grandmother or grandfather? (Or both!) [results published March 20, 1994] (Offsite-box 8)
  - NYS Contest 124. What weird thing does your friend or lover do just because he/she is the opposite sex? [results published March 27, 1994] (Offsite-box 8)
  - NYS Contest 125. What incident convinced you that you are really bad at some activity? [results published April 3, 1994] (Offsite-box 8)
  - NYS Contest 126. What did you and your imaginary friend used to do together? (And what was your buddy's name?) [results published April 10, 1994] (Offsite-box 8)
  - NYS Contest 127. What strange thing do you carry around with you? And has it ever come in handy? [results published April 17, 1994] (Offsite-box 8)
  - NYS Contest 128. Who did you know before they were famous—and what was already interesting about 'em? [results published April 24, 1994] (Offsite-box 8)
  - NYS Contest 129. What's the most amazing thing—good or bad—that ever happened to you at a dance? [results published May 1, 1994] (Offsite-box 8)
  - NYS Contest 130. What went completely wrong on a family outing that was supposed to be completely right? [results published May 8, 1994] (Offsite-box 8)
  - NYS Contest 131. What question have you always dreamed of a talk-show host asking you? [results published May 15, 1994] (Offsite-box 8)
  - NYS Contest 132. What's the strangest thing you've ever witnessed on the beach... or at the pool? [results published May 22, 1994] (Offsite-box 8)
  - NYS Contest 133. What's the wildest question you ever heard a child ask about religion? [results published June 5, 1994] (Offsite-box 8)
  - NYS Contest 134. When did a bug bug you the most? [results published June 12, 1994] (Offsite-box 8)
  - NYS Contest 135. What's the most interesting thing about the way you proposed marriage... or were proposed to? [results published June 19, 1994] (Offsite-box 8)
  - NYS Contest 136. What strange thing occurred while you were waiting for someone? [results published June 26, 1994] (Offsite-box 9)
  - NYS Contest 137. What's the most remarkable thing you ever received in the mail? [results published July 3, 1994] (Offsite-box 9)
  - NYS Contest 138. How do you choose your lottery numbers? [results published July 10, 1994] (Offsite-box 9)
  - NYS Contest 139. What's the wildest way you were ever asked out? [results published July 17, 1994] (Offsite-box 9)
  - NYS Contest 140. What's the most ridiculous thing you've ever done in public? [results published July 24, 1994] (Offsite-box 9)
  - NYS Contest 141. What strange thing did you invent as a child? Or what strange thing did your child invent? [results published July 31, 1994] (Offsite-box 9)
  - NYS Contest 142. How did your parents meet? (Grandparents are eligible, too, if you've got a great story!) [results published August 7, 1994] (Offsite-box 9)
  - NYS Contest 143. What silly little vacation incident or souvenir made the biggest impression on your child? Or what made the biggest impression on you as a vacationing kid? [results published August 14, 1994] (Offsite-box 9)
  - NYS Contest 144. How did an animal unexpectedly enter your life? [results published August 21, 1994] (Offsite-box 9)
  - NYS Contest 145. What's the most creative way you ever tormented your brother or sister... or vice versa? [results published August 28, 1994] (Offsite-box 9)
  - NYS Contest 146. What's the most embarrassing thing you ever wore to please someone else? [results published September 4, 1994] (Offsite-box 9)
  - NYS Contest 147. What strange phrase or expression do you use all the time? And where did it come from? [results published September 11, 1994] (Offsite-box 9)